<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tabular Expressions on</title><link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/docs/tabluar-expressions/</link><description>Recent content in Tabular Expressions on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/docs/tabluar-expressions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>project</title><link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/docs/tabluar-expressions/project/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/docs/tabluar-expressions/project/</guid><description>Convert an input row to an output row by keeping, dropping, or transforming rows.
Syntax #
project Column [= Expression], ... Parameters #
Name Type Required Description Column column Yes The column to appear in the output. Expression expression No An expression to calculate the value Example #
The following example will create an output table with columns date identical to the input and distance calculated as 0.00075 * steps.</description></item><item><title>render</title><link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/docs/tabluar-expressions/render/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/docs/tabluar-expressions/render/</guid><description>Render the input table as a visualisation for example a chart.
Syntax #
render Type [with PropertyName = PropertyValue, ...] Parameters #
Name Type Required Description Type enum Yes The type of visualisation linechart, barchart, or table. PropertyName name No The name of a property to pass to the render e.g. title. PropertyValue string or int No The value of the property. Example #
The following example will render the input table as a line chart with a title of &amp;ldquo;Step Chart&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>sort</title><link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/docs/tabluar-expressions/sort/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/docs/tabluar-expressions/sort/</guid><description>Sort the rows in a table by a given column optionally specifying a direction.
Syntax #
sort Column [Order] Parameters #
Name Type Required Description Column column Yes The column to sort the table by. Order asc or desc No The order to sort by, defaults to asc i.e. low to high. Example #
The following example will sort the table by the steps column in .
Steps | sort steps desc</description></item><item><title>summarise</title><link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/docs/tabluar-expressions/summarise/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/docs/tabluar-expressions/summarise/</guid><description>Summarise using aggregation function and a group.
Syntax #
summarise Column = Aggregation(Expression)[, ...] by Column Parameters #
Name Type Required Description Column 1 column Yes The new column to create. Column 2 column Yes The column to group by. Aggregation aggregation Yes The aggregation function such as sum(), avg(), etc. Expression expression Depends on Aggregation The expression to aggregate. Supported Aggregations #
Aggregation Description count() Count of the number of items dcount(expression) Count of the number of unique items sum(expression) Sum of the values of a given expression avg(expression) Average (mean) of the values of a given expression min(expression) Minimum of the values of a given expression max(expression) Maximum of the values of a given expression Example #
The following example will .</description></item><item><title>take</title><link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/docs/tabluar-expressions/take/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/docs/tabluar-expressions/take/</guid><description>Return up to a specified number of rows.
Syntax #
take N Parameters #
Name Type Required Description N int Yes Maximum number of rows to return Example #
The following example will return the first 10 rows from the &amp;ldquo;Steps&amp;rdquo;, if there are fewer than 10 rows in the table all rows will be returned.
Steps | take 10</description></item><item><title>where</title><link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/docs/tabluar-expressions/where/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/docs/tabluar-expressions/where/</guid><description>Select all rows where the provided condition is true.
Syntax #
where Condition Parameters #
Name Type Required Description Condition expression Yes Expression that evaluates to true or false. Example #
The following example will return rows where the steps count is 15,000 or more from the current month.
Steps | where steps &amp;gt;= 15000 and date &amp;gt;= beginning_of_the_month()</description></item></channel></rss>